Guide to the Bill Dixon Papers MSS.481
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II. Bennington College, 1964-1995, 2005; 88.26 Linear Feet in 30 record cartons, 29 flat boxes, 16 manuscript boxes, 4 tall LP boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 1 flat-file folder.; 40.26 Gigabytes in 42 digital files.
  - Subseries II.A: Class and Lecture Recordings, 1967-1994; 56.5 Linear Feet in 27 record cartons, 25 flat boxes, 3 LP boxes, and 1 manuscript box
    - Ensemble Class, April, 1988; cuid38401 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_253)
    - Ensemble Class, April, 1988; cuid38402 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_281)
    - Ensemble Class, April, 1988; cuid38403 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_283)
    - Tutorial -- Ellington, Coltrane, Parker, April, 1988; cuid38404 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1911, 481_1912)
    - Ensemble, April 6, 1988; cuid38405 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_818)
    - Improvisation, April 6, 1988; cuid38406 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1884)
    - Ensemble Class, May, 1988; cuid38407 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_276)
    - Ensemble Class, May, 1988; cuid38408 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_296)
    - Ensemble Class, May 1988; cuid38409 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_227)
    - Ensemble Class, May, 1988; cuid38410 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_255)
    - Ensemble Class, May, 1988; cuid38411 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_279)
    - Tutorial -- Ellington, Coltrane, Parker, May, 1988; cuid38412 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1805, Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1920)
    - Ensemble, May 6, 1988; cuid38413 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_817)
    - Ensemble Class, May 12, 1988; cuid38414 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_254)
    - Ensemble Class, May 13, 1988; cuid38415 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_220, Box 21, Audiocassette 481_282)
      Marked "Original"
    - Tutorial -- Ellington, Coltrane, Parker, May 14, 1988; cuid38416 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1899, 481_1913)
    - Ensemble -- Arthur Brooks Conducting, May 20, 1988; cuid38417 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_811)
    - Bill Dixon Seminar on Ellington, Coltrane, Parker; Voice: D. Karthas, May 21, 1988; cuid38418 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1852)
    - Black Music II -- P. Murray, May 25, 1988; cuid38419 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1220)
    - Ensemble Class, May 26, 1988; cuid38420 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_280)
    - Ensemble Class -- Van Dongen's Work, June 2, 1988; cuid38421 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_278)
    - Ensemble Class -- Tony Wilson, June 3, 1988; cuid38422 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_228)
    - Ellington, Coltrane, Parker, June 4, 1988; cuid38423 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1875)
    - Black Music I, September 14, 1988; cuid38424 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1248)
    - Ensemble Class, September 15, 1988; cuid38425 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_252)
    - Improvisation, September 15, 1988; cuid38426 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1883)
    - Ensemble Class, September 16, 1988; cuid38427 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_248)
    - Tutorial -- Hawkins-Murray, September 18, 1988; cuid38428 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_816)
    - Workshop, September 19, 1988; cuid38429 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_246)
    - Introduction to Black Music, September 20, 1988; cuid38430 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_1166)
    - Improvisation, September 22, 1988; cuid38431 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1882)
    - Workshop, September 27, 1988; cuid38432 (Box 45, Audiocassette 481_2562)
    - Black Music I, September 28, 1988; cuid38433 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1247)
    - Seminar -- Robeson, October 2, 1988; cuid38434 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1803, Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1812)
    - Black Music I -- McRae, Rollins, Taylor, Coltrane, October 12, 1988; cuid38435
      - Audio (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1236)
      - Papers (Box 213, Folder 14)
    - Ensemble -- "Here's That Rainy Day" Workshop, October 18, 1988; cuid38436 (Box 45, Audiocassette 481_2559)
      Featuring D. Cotton (Voice) and Bill Dixon (Piano)
    - Introduction to Black Music, October 19, 1988; cuid38437 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_1184)
    - Black Music I, October 19, 1988; cuid38438 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1250)
    - Ensemble III, October 27, 1988; cuid38439 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_815)
    - Ensemble III -- Workshop, November 1, 1988; cuid38441 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_810)
    - Ensemble Class, November 3, 1988; cuid38440 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_251)
    - Black Music I, November 30, 1988; cuid38442 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1237)
    - Ensemble Class, circa 1989; cuid38286 (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_856)
    - Introduction to Black Music, 1989; cuid38453 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1202)
    - Black Music II, Spring, 1989; cuid38454 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1218)
    - Creative Process Class, Black Music II Presentations, Spring, 1989; cuid38455 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1854)
    - Creative Process Class, Black Music II Presentations, Spring, 1989; cuid38456 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1892)
    - Ensemble III, Spring 1989; cuid38443 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_235)
    - Ensemble III, Spring 1989; cuid38444 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_236)
    - Ensemble III, Spring 1989; cuid38445 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_237)
    - Black Music II, March 15, 1989; cuid38457 (Box 34, Audiocassette 481_1277)
    - Black Music II, March 22, 1989; cuid38458 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1213)
    - Black Music II, March 29, 1989; cuid38459 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1216)
    - Ensemble Class -- Including "Small Episodes", Fall, 1989; cuid38451 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_261, 481_262)
    - Intro to Black Music -- Keyboard Harmony, Improvisation, September 14, 1989; cuid38446 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_812)
    - Introduction to Black Music, September 27, 1989; cuid38460 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_1194)
    - Introduction to Black Music -- Miles Davis, September 27, 1989; cuid38461 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1240)
    - Introduction to Black Music, October 4, 1989; cuid38463 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1235)
    - Introduction to Black Music -- Music Tape, October 4, 1989; cuid38462 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_1187)
    - Ensemble III -- Including "Small Episodes", November 2, 1989; cuid38464 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_234)
    - Ensemble Class, 1989-1990; cuid38292 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_260)
    - Ensemble Class, 1989-1990; cuid38447 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_256)
    - Ensemble Class, 1989-1990; cuid38448 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_257)
    - Ensemble Class, 1989-1990; cuid38449 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_258)
    - Ensemble Class, 1989-1990; cuid38450 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_259)
    - Ensemble Class, circa 1989-1990; cuid38452 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_832)
    - Ensemble III, circa 1990; cuid38294 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_823)
    - Ensemble Class, circa 1990; cuid38295 (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_840)
    - Ensemble Class, circa 1990; cuid38296 (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_846)
    - Ensemble Class, circa 1990; cuid38297 (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_848)
    - Jennings Class -- Adrian Guest Lecture on Stan Hasselgard and Django Reinhardt, circa 1990; cuid38299 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_1169)
    - Black Music II, Spring, 1990; cuid38475 (Box 34, Audiocassette 481_1276)
    - Ensemble Class, Fall, 1990; cuid38465 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_833)
    - Ensemble, Fall, 1990; cuid38467 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_835)
    - Ensemble III, Fall, 1990; cuid38466 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_834)
    - Ensemble III, Fall, 1990; cuid38468 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_836)
    - Ensemble III, Fall, 1990; cuid38469 (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_847)
    - Introduction to Black Music, Fall, 1990; cuid38472 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1243)
    - Introduction to Black Music, Fall, 1990; cuid38473 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1244)
    - Introduction to Black Music, Fall, 1990; cuid38474 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1249)
    - Introduction to Black Music, 1990s; cuid38470 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1226)
    - Lecture, circa 1990s; cuid38471 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1241)
    - Ensemble III, 1991; cuid38477 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_814)
    - Ensemble III, Workshops on 9/24 and 10/1, 1991; cuid38476 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_790)
    - Ensemble Class and Rehearsal, Carriage Barn, circa 1991; cuid38314 (Box 98, Audiocassette 481_788)
      Audiocassette 481_788 in Box 98 was identified as moldy in September, 2022. This item is currently isolated from other items by housing it in a polyethylene bag with a desiccated board and RH monitor strip. If this strip indicates an RH greater than 50%, the Preservation department should be contacted ASAP. Do not open this packaging without contacting the Preservation Department.
    - Introduction to Black Music -- Lecture on Cecil Taylor, Fall, 1991; cuid38481 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1861)
    - Introduction to Black Music -- Miles Davis, 1991; cuid38480 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1211)
    - Ensemble III, Fall, 1991; cuid38478 (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_844)
    - Ensemble III, September 6, 1991; cuid38482 (Box 98, Audiocassette 481_852)
      Audiocassette 481_852 in Box 98 was identified as moldy in September, 2022. This item is currently isolated from other items by housing it in a polyethylene bag with a desiccated board and RH monitor strip. If this strip indicates an RH greater than 50%, the Preservation department should be contacted ASAP. Do not open this packaging without contacting the Preservation Department.
    - Ensemble III, September 7, 1991; cuid38483 (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_853)
    - Ensemble III, September 12, 1991; cuid38484 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_837)
    - Ensemble Class, September 13, 1991; cuid38485 (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_850)
    - Introduction to Black Music -- Lecture on Miles Davis, Thelonious Monk, John Coltrane, September 18, 1991; cuid38486 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_1186)
    - Ensemble Class, September 19, 1991; cuid38487 (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_851)
    - Tutorial on Miles Davis, October, 1991; cuid38488 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1886)
    - Tutorial on Miles Davis, October, 1991; cuid38489 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1888)
    - Tutorial on Miles Davis, October, 1991; cuid38490 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1889)
    - Black Music II -- Lecture on Miles Davis, October, 1991; cuid38491 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1890)
    - Ensemble III, October 17, 1991; cuid38492 (Box 98, Audiocassette 481_854)
      Audiocassette 481_854 in Box 98 was identified as moldy in September, 2022. This item is currently isolated from other items by housing it in a polyethylene bag with a desiccated board and RH monitor strip. If this strip indicates an RH greater than 50%, the Preservation department should be contacted ASAP. Do not open this packaging without contacting the Preservation Department.
    - Tutorial on Miles Davis, October 17, 1991; cuid38493 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1887)
    - Introduction to Black Music -- Bill Cole Guest Lecture on Miles Davis and John Coltrane, October 30, 1991; cuid38494 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_1198)
      Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank; Duration: 47 min
    - Ensemble III, October 31, 1991; cuid38495 (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_855)
    - Ensemble III -- Williams College Rehearsal, November, 1991; cuid38496 (Box 98, Audiocassette 481_838)
      Audiocassette 481_838 in Box 98 was identified as moldy in September, 2022. This item is currently isolated from other items by housing it in a polyethylene bag with a desiccated board and RH monitor strip. If this strip indicates an RH greater than 50%, the Preservation department should be contacted ASAP. Do not open this packaging without contacting the Preservation Department.
    - Intro to Black Music -- Lecture on Music of the Sixties, November 6, 1991; cuid38497 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1885)
    - Ensemble III, 1991-1992; cuid38479 (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_845)
    - Lecture, Demonstration, circa 1992; cuid38376 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_964)
    - Black Music Lecture, circa 1992; cuid38377 (Box 33, Audiocassette 481_1214)
    - Arthur Brooks -- Ensemble V, Fall, 1992; cuid37361 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1616, 481_1618)
    - Bill Dixon Lecture on Cecil Taylor, Fall, 1992; cuid38498 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1836)
    - Bill Dixon Lecture on Cecil Taylor, Fall, 1992; cuid38499 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1856)
    - Bill Dixon Lecture on Cecil Taylor, Fall, 1992; cuid38500 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1857)
    - Bill Dixon Lecture on Cecil Taylor, Fall, 1992; cuid38501 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1858)
    - Bill Dixon Lecture on Cecil Taylor, Fall, 1992; cuid38502 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1859)
    - Bill Dixon Lecture on Cecil Taylor, Fall, 1992; cuid38503 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1860)
    - Ben Young Lecture on Cecil Taylor, October 17, 1992; cuid38506 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1876, 481_1902)
    - Bill Dixon Lecture on Cecil Taylor, 1992-1993; cuid38504 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1862)
    - Class on Duke Ellington, 1992-1993; cuid38505 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1914)
    - Ensemble III, 1993; cuid38507 (Box 67, Vhs 481_027)
    - Ensemble III, Ben Young -- Quinn Johnson, Fall, 1993; cuid38508 (Box 67, Vhs 481_031)
      Duration: 29 minutes
    - Course on Cecil Taylor, Spring, 1993; cuid38510 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1908)
    - Course on Cecil Taylor, Spring, 1993; cuid38511 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1909)
    - Course on Cecil Taylor, Spring, 1993; cuid38512 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1910)
    - Courses on Cecil Taylor, Keyboard Harmony, and the Idea of Atonalism, Spring, 1993; cuid38509 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1907)
    - Lecture, May 5-6, 1993; cuid38513
      - Video -- 1 of 2 (Box 67, Vhs 481_026)
      - Video -- 2 of 2 (Box 67, Vhs 481_038)
    - Bill Dixon Lecture on Cecil Taylor, May 22, 1993; cuid38514 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1906)
    - Tutorial -- Improvisation, June, 1993; cuid38535 (Box 78, Vhs 481_2387)
      Featuring Joe Bloom on piano and Bill Dixon on trumpet and flugelhorn.
    - Ensemble Class, 1994; cuid38516 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_820)
    - Lecture on Improvisation, February 21, 1994; cuid38517 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_594)
    - Ensemble Class, March, 1994; cuid38518 (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_843)
    - L'Opera -- First Class on Bill Dixon, March 12, 1994; cuid38519
      - Audio (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1917, 481_1918)
      - Video -- 1 of 2, cuid38519A (Box 78, Vhs 481_2398)
      - Video -- 2 of 2, cuid38519B (Box 78, Vhs 481_2413)
    - Class 2 -- Ben Young, "This is Our Strategy" and "Bird's Word", March 26, 1994; cuid38520
      - Video -- 1 of 2, cuid38520A (Box 78, Vhs 481_2412)
      - Video -- 2 of 2, cuid38520B (Box 78, Vhs 481_2418)
    - Class, April 9, 1994; cuid38521
      - Video -- 1 of 2, cuid38521A (Box 78, Vhs 481_2405)
        Duration: 27 minutes
      - Video -- 2 of 2, cuid38521B (Box 78, Vhs 481_2408)
    - L'Opera Class with Guest Lecturer Arthur Brooks, April 23, 1994; cuid38522
      - Audio (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1815, Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1919)
      - Video -- 1 of 2, cuid38522A (Box 77, Vhs 481_2419)
      - Video -- 2 of 2, cuid38522B (Box 77, Vhs 481_2420)
        Duration: 118 minutes
    - Ensemble III Special Class, April 24, 1994; cuid38523 (Box 78, Vhs 481_2399)
    - Ensemble and Guests, May, 1994; cuid38524 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_821)
    - L'Opera Class with Guest Lecturer: Anthony Braxton, May 7, 1994
      - Audio (Box 23, Audiocassette 481_532)
      - Video, cuid38525 (Box 78, Vhs 481_2409)
    - Ensemble III -- "Sisyphus 2", May 20, 1994; cuid38526 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2256)
      Featuring guests Zappa, Curry, Bender, Eneidi, Arthur Brooks, and Laurence Cook.
    - L'Opera Class with Guest Lecturer Chris Bakriges, May 21, 1994
      - Audio (Box 40, Vhs 481_1915)
      - Video, cuid38527 (Box 77, Vhs 481_2617)
        Duration: 93 minutes
    - Embouchure Studies, May 24-25, 1994; cuid38528
      Video by Vincent Carte
      - Video -- 1 of 2, cuid38528B (Box 77, Vhs 481_2616)
      - Video -- 2 of 2, cuid38528A (Box 77, Vhs 481_2426)
    - Ensemble III -- M. Springer Piece, Bill Dixon Solos, Notated Piece, May 26, 1994; cuid38529
      Duration: 249 minutes (in three parts)
      - Audio (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_839)
      - Video -- 1 of 3 (Box 67, Vhs 481_021)
      - Video -- 2 of 3 (Box 67, Vhs 481_028)
      - Video -- 3 of 3 (Box 67, Vhs 481_032)
    - Ensemble III -- M. Springer, Bill Dixon, May 27, 1994; cuid38530
      Duration: 109 minutes (in two parts)
      - Audio (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_819)
      - Video -- 1 of 2 (Box 67, Vhs 481_029)
      - Video -- 2 of 2 (Box 67, Vhs 481_030)
    - Good Lecture, June 2, 1994; cuid38531 (Box 67, Vhs 481_012)
    - Ensemble III, Dinner, June 3, 1994; cuid38532 (Box 67, Vhs 481_013)
      Duration: 33 minutes
    - L'Opera Class with Lecture by Bill Dixon, June 4, 1994
      - Audio (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1916)
      - Video, cuid38533 (Box 78, Vhs 481_2382)
    - Ensemble III with Guest Mark Sutton, June 6, 1994; cuid38534 (Box 67, Vhs 481_035)
    - Bill Dixon on Ellington, September 17, 1994; cuid38536
      - Video -- 1 of 2, cuid38536A (Box 77, Vhs 481_2422)
        Duration: 8 minutes
      - Video -- 2 of 2, cuid38536B (Box 77, Vhs 481_2423)
        Duration: 91 minutes
    - Bill Dixon on Ellington, October 1, 1994; cuid38537
      - Video -- 1 of 2, cuid38537A (Box 77, Vhs 481_2427)
      - Video -- 2 of 2, cuid38537B (Box 77, Vhs 481_2618)
    - Ellington Class -- Lecture and Tutorials, October 1, 1994; cuid37881 (Box 78, Vhs 481_2402)
    - Impromptu Workshop, October 6, 1994; cuid38538 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1998)
    - Bill Dixon on Ellington, October 15, 1994; cuid38539
      - Video -- 1 of 3, cuid38539A (Box 77, Vhs 481_2612)
      - Video -- 2 of 3, cuid38539B (Box 77, Vhs 481_2614)
        Duration: 80 minutes
      - Video -- 3 of 3, cuid38539C (Box 77, Vhs 481_2615)
    - Ensemble III, October 28, 1994; cuid38540 (Box 78, Vhs 481_2386)
    - Bill Dixon on Ellington, October 29, 1994; cuid38541
      - Video -- 1 of 2, cuid38541A (Box 77, Vhs 481_2425)
      - Video -- 2 of 2, cuid38541B (Box 77, Vhs 481_2611)
        Duration: 48 minutes
    - Bill Dixon on Ellington, December 3, 1994; cuid38542
      - Video -- 1 of 2, cuid38542A (Box 77, Vhs 481_2424)
      - Video -- 2 of 2, cuid38542B (Box 77, Vhs 481_2428)
    - Ellington Class, December 10, 1994; cuid38543 (Box 78, Vhs 481_2414)
      Duration: 123 minutes
    - Advanced Composition for Dancers and Choreographers, Undated; cuid38545 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1839)
    - Aesthetics as they Relate to Black Music Class -- Guest Lecture by Larry Neal from Williams College, Undated; cuid38546 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1813)
      Duration: 96 minutes.
    - Aesthetics Lecture Class, Undated; cuid38547 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1869)
    - Basic Music Instruction Lecture, Undated; cuid38548 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_1174)
    - Bill Dixon Discussing Music with the Class, Undated; cuid38549 (Box 49, Quarter inch audio reel 481_110)
    - Bill Dixon Ensemble, Bennington College, Undated; cuid38550 (Box 67, Vhs 481_014)
      Duration: 98 minutes
    - Bill Dixon Tutorial, Undated; cuid38551 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_1173)
    - Bill Dixon's Ensemble -- 11/1 class 17, 11/2 Class 18, Undated; cuid38552 (Box 22, Audiocassette 481_313)
    - Bill Evans, Bill Dixon Ensemble Continued, Undated; cuid38553 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_785)
    - Black Aesthetics Lecture Class, Undated; cuid38554 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1802)
    - Black Criticism Class -- Cecil Taylor, Undated; cuid38555 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1903, 481_1904)
    - Black Criticism Lecture Class -- Nang and David, Undated; cuid38556 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1871)
    - Black Music Ensemble, Undated; cuid38557 (Box 51, Quarter inch audio reel 481_147)
    - Black Music Ensemble, Undated; cuid38558 (Box 51, Quarter inch audio reel 481_160)
    - Black Music Ensemble Auditions (2nd Semester), Undated; cuid38559 (Box 98, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2090)
    - Black Music II, Undated; cuid38560 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_801)
    - RESTRICTED: Black Music II -- Student Presentation on Miles Davis, "So What" by RESTRICTED, Undated; cuid38631 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_466)
    - Black Music Lecture Class, Undated; cuid38561 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_1168)
    - Black Music Seminar Intro, Undated; cuid38562 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1865)
    - Class, Undated; cuid38563
    - Class in Black Criticism by Bill Dixon and Richard Tristman, Undated; cuid38564 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1864)
    - Class in Jennings, Undated; cuid38565 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_828)
    - Class Lecture by Bill Dixon, Undated; cuid38566
    - Class Presentations -- Intro by Student, Undated; cuid38567 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_1156)
    - Class Rehearsal, Undated; cuid38987 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1107)
    - Clayton Reilly -- Aesthetics as They Relate to Black Music, Undated; cuid38568 (Box 57, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1433, Box 63, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2315)
    - Clayton Reilly -- Lecture to General College Community, Undated; cuid38569 (Box 63, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2214, Box 52, Quarter inch audio reel 481_427)
    - Collaborative Process Class, Undated; cuid38570 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1878, 481_1879)
    - Composition Music Tutorial, Undated; cuid38571 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1840)
    - Composition and Performance Class, Jennings, Undated; cuid38572 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_452, 481_453)
    - Composition C -- Dance, Undated; cuid38573 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1838)
    - Composition Class, Undated; cuid38574 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1894)
    - Composition with E. Zinman, Undated; cuid38575 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1807, 481_1808)
    - Contemporary Improvisation for the Dancer - Dave Maxwell, Undated; cuid38576 (Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2064)
    - Contemporary Studies in Black Music, Undated; cuid38577 (Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2060)
    - Contemporary Studies in Black Music Lecture, Undated; cuid38578 (Box 63, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2343)
    - Creative Process Class -- Dance Student Presentations, Painting, Etc., Undated; cuid38579 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1833)
    - Dance, Students' work, Undated; cuid38580 (Box 74, Vhs 481_2105)
      This video could not be digitized due to its regional encoding system (PAL).
    - Dixon, Coltrane, Undated; cuid38581 (Box 78, Vhs 481_2406)
      Duration: 70 minutes
    - Dixon lectures on faculty meeting and tenure, undated; cuid41265 (Box 80, Half inch video reel 481_2654)
    - Elements of Contemporary Composition and Improvisation, Undated; cuid38582 (Box 61, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2277)
    - Elements of Contemporary Composition and Improvisation, Undated; cuid38583 (Box 56, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1414)
    - Elements of Contemporary Improvisation - Henry Carnes, Undated; cuid38584 (Box 50, Quarter inch audio reel 481_185)
    - Elements of Swing Class, Undated; cuid38585 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1816)
    - Ensemble, Undated; cuid38544 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2480)
    - Ensemble, Undated; cuid38594
    - Ensemble Class, Undated; cuid38586 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_786)
    - Ensemble Class, Undated; cuid38587 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_793)
    - Ensemble Class, Undated; cuid38588 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_831)
    - Ensemble Class, Undated; cuid38589 (Box 30, Audiocassette 481_881)
    - Ensemble Class, Undated; cuid38590 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_908)
    - Ensemble Class, Undated; cuid38591 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_916)
    - Ensemble Class, Undated; cuid38592 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_923)
    - Ensemble Class, Undated; cuid38593 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_265)
    - Ensemble Class -- Piano Solo Demonstration, Undated; cuid38595 (Box 21, Audiocassette 481_264)
    - Ensemble Class and Bill Dixon Bass Duets, Undated; cuid38596 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_796)
    - Ensemble Class With Electric Guitar, Undated; cuid38597 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_824)
    - Ensemble Class -- "Night and Day," "For Franz," Bill Dixon on Trumpet, Undated; cuid38598 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_929)